STEPHEN HUMBURG

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

AUSTIN, TX

30 years of experience developing high performing on-prem and cloud-based business solutions.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Deep knowledge and experience with every aspect of designing, developing, deploying, tracking, maintaining, and enhancing on-prem and cloud-based applications. Experienced leader and mentor of fellow developers. Experience with the analysis and improvement of the software development process.

Technologies: .Net, Angular, API, Arm/Bicep, AWS, Azure, C#, DevOps, Lambda Functions, Java, MVC, Oracle, PHP, Postgres, Razor, React, SQL Server, Terraform, WPF

EXPERIENCE

05/2022 - 12/2023 - Team Lead Software Engineer - Accenture

Specialized in hybrid cloud solutions. Analyzed and suggested software delivery process improvements. Assisted setting up client's Azure infrastructure using Bicep. Set up basic ETL process for Power BI report generation. Led fellow developers through mentorship and brown bag presentations.

07/2018 - 03/2022 - Lead Developer - Cox Automotive

Brought iRecon proof of concept to market. Co-led brownfield application development. Used Terraform to deploy and maintain AWS infrastructure. Designed time tracking system to aggregate start/stop of different tasks for process improvement analysis.

11/2015 - 07/2018 - Senior Software Engineer - Blizzard Entertainment

Worked with a team to support customer service applications to interface with finance, subscriptions, and all games. Developed APIs which were deployed to six global regions. Involved in GDPR improvements.

04/2012 - 11/2015 - Lead Developer - Acryness Inc.

Led developer team to redesign entire SaaS delivery pipeline, infrastructure, web application, and credit/eCheck payment process. Redesigned deployment process from a multi-hour roll forward model to a blue-green model. Implemented several HL7 interfaces to import client data.

11/2010 - 04/2012 - Senior Web Application Developer - Hatteras Search Group

Delivered training sessions on Test Driven Development. Led development of a unit testing framework. Assisted Mecklenburg County in refactoring the Mecklenburg County Sheriff's Office's Arrest Processing system. Responsible for implementing system designed by project architect. Designed and submitted database schemas.

03/2009 - 11/2010 - Front End Engineer - iContact

Worked on the team responsible for the CSR access to account/billing information. Tasked with forming and advising the Templates Team, the highest business priority at the time. The Templates Team comprised of an in-house team, a local contracted team, and a near shore team. Assisted in the development of a custom Salesforce application to seamlessly integrate with iContact's API.

10/2005 - 02/2009 - Senior Software Developer - CC Intelligent Solutions

Provided supplemental staffing for two clients and worked with an in-house team. Assisted with conversion of a VB6 application to VB.Net for the Secretary of State, Charitable Solicitation License Division. Rewrote the security class library used by all web-based applications for the NC Division of Information Resource Management (DIRM). Supported and enhanced a document storage system used by 12 state divisions. Converted four production applications from Visual Studio 6 to Visual Studio .NET. Converted an application from Apache/Perl to MS IIS/C#. Assisted with maintenance and enhancement of a military project using SharePoint, WCF, Web Parts, and Workflows. Created a proof-of-concept project involving workflows on multiple SharePoint servers.

07/1999 - 10/2005 - Senior Application Developer - Keane Inc.

Provided supplemental staffing for clients such as Glaxo Smith Kline, GE Capital Mortgage, and the State of North Carolina. Assisted in completing two .Net projects, and three web based document/content management systems. Specifically requested by a client to return for a second assignment. Functioned as team lead for two clients. Increased speed of client's nightly batch application by 500%. Received client award for 65% reduction in the average number of subscription requests that took more than 1 day to process.

08/1998 - 07/1999 - Web Application Developer - CareerShop.com

Maintained and enhanced company's resume and job posting web site. Developed a web-based document flow system to enhance the employee hiring process of clients. Administered company server applications: MS Index Server, MS IIS, MS SQL Server, and MS Transaction Server.

08/1996 - 08/1998 - Web Programmer - Orange County Government

Assisted with the development of an inmate search application used by bail bondsmen. Developed two other web-based projects to dynamically access databases. Maintained the county's web site pages, images, and navigation.

04/1994 - 03/1996 - Program Analyst - Lockheed Martin

Received Secret Security Clearance by the US Government. Developed software to rigorously test code produced by certified engineers in Jovial J73. Developed an HTML web site to provide information about team projects.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science – Computer Science – University of Central Florida